Register of the Guy Jean Pauker Papers, 1928-1996
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1952-1974 (Box 133-141)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Center for International Studies, Project on the Economic and Political Development of Indonesia
    - The Impact of Capital-Intensive Agriculture on Peasant Social Structure: A Case Study, Clifford Geertz, June 1956 (Folder 12)
    - The Indonesian Economy: The Export Crops Sector, William C. Holliger, November 30, 1953 (Folder 13)
    - The Indonesian Economy: The Food Crops Sector, William C. Hollinger, June 12, 1953 (Folder 14)
    - Indonesian National Planning Bureau Report, November 4, 1953 (Folder 15)
    - Indonesia's Development Plan, Benjamin Higgins, 1957 (Folder 16)
    - Indonesia's Investment Requirements, Eugene Grasberg, September 1955 (Folder 17)
    - Interactions of Cycles and Trends, Benjamin Higgins, November 22, 1954 (Folder 18)
    - International Trade, the Balance of Payments and the Economic Development of Indonesia, William C. Hollinger, August 12, 1954 (Folder 19)
    - Islam in Indonesia, selective bibliography, Hedwig Schleiffer, 1955 (Folder 20)
    - Progress and trip reports, 1953-55 (Folder 21)
    - Proposed agenda for meeting of Indonesian officials, June 1954 (Box 138., Folder 1)
    - Quantitative studies (Folder 2)
    - The Role of Local Finance in Indonesian Economic Development, Douglas S. Paauw, 1954 (Folder 3)
    - Social Accounting in Underdeveloped Areas, William C. Hollinger, April 2, 1954 (Folder 4)
    - Sociological Background of Development
      - Local Government in Rural Central Java, Robert R. Ray, 1956 (Folder 5)
      - Religious Belief and Economic Behavior in a Central Javanese Town, Clifford Geertz, 1956 (Folder 6)
    - The Trade Agreements Program of Indonesia, 1950-55, September 1955 (Folder 7)
    - Travel reimbursement (Folder 8-9)
  - Microfilm orders (Folder 10)
  - Modelski, George, The New Emerging Forces, 1963 (Folder 11/12)
  - Morris, Roger, Following the Scenario - Reflections on Five Case Histories in the Mode and Aftermath of CIA Intervention, September 1974 (Folder 13)
  - Netherlands, clippings (Folder 14)
  - Paauw, Douglas S.
    - Address, Embassy of Indonesia, Washington, D.C., December 21, 1954 (Folder 15)
    - Background Material on Indonesian Fiscal System, June 3, 1953 (Folder 16)
    - The Case for Decentralized Financing of Economic Development in Indonesia, reprint, The Far Eastern Quarterly, Vol. XV, No. 1, November 1955 (Folder 17)
    - Curriculum vitae (Folder 18)
    - Export Taxes in Indonesia, October 22, 1952 (Folder 19)
    - The High Cost of Political Instability in Indonesia, 1957-58, n.d. (Folder 20)
    - Immediate Obstacles to Effective Economic Planning in Indonesia, n.d. (Folder 21)
    - Indonesia's Foreign Exchange Certificate System, December 8, 1952 (Folder 22)
    - Indonesian fiscal structure, 1953 (Folder 23)
    - Indonesian tax structure and tax burden, 1929-1953 (Folder 24)
    - Preliminary Statements of Topics of Interest at the Village Level, n.d. (Folder 25)
    - Research Plan for Indonesian Economic Development, February 18, 1953 (Folder 26)
    - The Role of Local Finance in Indonesian Economic Development, 1954 (Folder 27)
    - Some Notes on Fiscal Structure and Economic Development in Indonesia, June 5, 1953 (Folder 28)
    - Taxation and Economic Development in Indonesia, October 9, 1952 (Folder 29)
    - World Markets and the Dynamics of the Indonesian Economy, December 19, 1952 (Folder 30)
  - Pacific Island, Northern Mariana, Caroline and Marshall Islands trust territory (Folder 31)
  - Petkovic, Ranko, The Return of Indonesia? article, Review of International Affairs, Vol. XVII, No. 389, June 1966 (Folder 32)
  - Rodrigues, John (Folder 33)
  - Scalapino, R.A., The Impact of the Widening Sino-Soviet Dispute on the Left Wing Movement in the Afro-Asian World, circa 1964 (Folder 34)
  - Schmitt, Hans, Determinants of Income in Burma, Indonesia and the Philippines, February 20, 1957 (Folder 35)
  - Scott, Ray (Box 139., Folder 1)
  - Second African-Asian Conference, Djakarta, April 1964
    - Documents (Folder 2)
    - Proceedings of the meeting of ministers (Folder 3)
  - Simon, Sheldon, The Broken Triangle: Peking, Djakarta and the PKI, September 1967 (Folder 4-5)
  - Sjahrir, Sutan, The World Today, November 4, 1956 (Folder 6)
  - Soedjatmoto
    - Japan: Architect of a Post-Nuclear World Order? December 14, 1972 (Folder 7)
    - The Role of the Medium and Small Nations in the New Asia-Pacific Setting, January 27, 1973 (Folder 8)
  - Southeast Asia
    - General (Folder 9)
    - Fischer, Joseph, Universities and the Political Process in Southeast Asia, n.d. (Folder 10)
    - Japanese occupation, 1939-1940 (Folder 11)
    - Nugroho, Southeast Asian Perceptions of the Future in the Region, May 15, 1972 (Folder 12)
    - Students' papers (Folder 13-14)
  - Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group (Box 140., Folder 1)
  - Sumitro, D. (Folder 2)
  - Third Conference of Non-Aligned Countries, Lusaka, Zambia, September 8-10, 1970 (Folder 3)
  - Tung, Jee Chong (Folder 4)
  - United States
    - Department of State
      - Bureau of Intelligence and Research
        - Chinese Communist World Outlook, June 1962 (Folder 5)
        - World Strength of the Communist Party Organizations
          - January 1962 (Folder 6)
          - January 1963 (Folder 7)
          - January 1964 (Folder 8)
      - International Educational Exchange Service, Foreign Leader Program (Folder 9)
    - Embassy, Djakarta, Personnel and telephone directory, August 1957 (Folder 10)
    - Government Architect-Engineer Questionnaire Form 251 (Folder 11)
    - Policy in Southern Asia, a Soviet view of, 1962 (Box 141., Folder 1)
  - University of California, political science and public administration courses (Folder 2)
  - University of Indonesia, Institute for Economic and Social Research, Smallholders Rubber in Indonesia, by Kenneth D. Thomas, August 1957 (Folder 3)
  - Van Der Kroef, Justus M.
    - ASEAN's Security Needs and Policies, article, Pacific Affairs, Vol. 47, No. 2, Summer 1974 (Folder 4)
    - The West New Guinea Settlement - It's Origins and Implications, article, Orbis, Spring 1963 (Folder 5)
  - Van Der Veur, Paul W.
    - New Guinea Annexations and the Origin of the Irian Boundary, reprint, Australian Outlook, Vol. 18, No. 3, December 1964 (Folder 6)
    - Political Advancement in Papua - New Guinea, 1964-65, reprint, The Journal of Pacific History, Vol. 1, 1966 (Folder 7)
    - Political Future of Papua - New Guinea, reprint, Australian Outlook, Vol. 20, No. 2, August 1966 (Folder 8)
    - The United Nations in West Irian: A Critique, reprint, International Organization, Vol. XVII, No. 1, 1964 (Folder 9)
  - Vizzard, William R., Prisoner of War Policy in Relation to Changing Concepts of War, n.d. (Folder 10)
  - Walker, Sir Walter, How Borneo Was Won, The Round Table, January 1969 (Folder 11)
  - Warbey, William, The Mad War in Borneo, article, Tribune (London), February 7, 1964 (Folder 12)
  - Weinstein, Franklin B., The Uses of Foreign Policy in Indonesia: An Approach to the Analysis of Foreign Policy in the Less Developed Countries, September 1970 (Folder 13)
  - Wertheim, W.F., Society As a Composite of Conflicting Value Systems, 1959 (Folder 14)
  - Yaacob, Ibrahim, Persoalan Tentang Konfederasi Bangsa-Bangsa Seketurunan Melayu (The Question on the Confederation of Nations of the Malay Race Origin), July 8, 1963 (Folder 15)
  - Zavodsky, I.A., West Irian, March 1963 (Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 17)
- CARD FILE (Box 142-175)
  Card files listing research notes, biographical information, excerpts and citations from published sources pertaining to Indonesia arranged chronologically and alphabetically by subject.
  - ABRI (Box 142.)
  - Action fronts
  - AD Coord. bodies
  - Artists, authors
  - Biographical file
    - A-H
    - I-S (Box 143.)
    - S-Z (Box 144.)
  - Businessmen (Box 145.)
  - China
  - Chinese
  - Chronological file
    - 1955-57
    - 1957-58 (Box 146.)
    - 1958 (Box 147.)
    - 1958-59 (Box 148.)
    - 1959-1961 (Box 149.)
    - 1961-62 (Box 150.)
    - 1962 (Box 151.)
  - Corruption
  - D.I.
  - Domestic affairs
  - Dutch colonial administration
  - Dutch-Indonesian relations
  - Dwikora
  - Economic affairs
  - Economy, Indonesian
  - Educators and social workers (Box 152.)
  - Elections
  - Engineers and technicians
  - FBIS
  - FBIS (Box 153.)
  - FBIS (Box 154.)
  - Film boycott (Box 155.)
  - Front Nasional
  - Future of parties
  - Government officials
  - Guerillas
  - Illegality
  - Internal politics, Spring 1962
  - Internal security
  - International relations
  - IPKI
  - IPRI
  - IWA
  - Jogja Charter
  - June 55 Affair
  - Konfrontasi
  - Labor leaders
  - Lawyers and legal experts
  - Local Chiefs
  - Local government members
  - Masiumi
  - Medical personnel
  - Meetings of Panglima
  - Military personnel
  - Military regime
  - Minorities
  - Murba
  - Nasakom
  - Nasution (Box 156.)
  - Netherlands
  - NU
  - October 17
  - Pantja Tunggal
  - Parties
  - Partindo
  - PDII
  - PNI
  - Permesta
  - Philippines
  - PKI
  - PKI (Box 157.)
  - Polemics
  - Political groups
  - PRRI
  - Press and radio
  - Public administration
  - Public administration (Box 158.)
  - Regional problems
  - Regionalism
  - Religion
  - Religious leaders
  - RMS
  - Security
  - SOB
  - Soviets
  - Succesion struggle
  - Suharto
  - Sukarno
  - Tentara Peladjar
  - TNI
  - UN
  - US
  - Trials, hearings and verdicts of participants in the 30 September 1965 coup (Box 159-167.)
  - Veterans (Box 167.)
  - West Irian
  - Women and youth leaders
  - YAP
  - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous (Box 168-175.)
- PHOTOGRAPHS AND SLIDES, circa 1950-1960, 145 prints / 5 envelopes / 278 slides (Cabinet 10.A-V, slide cabinet)
  - 145 prints depicting scenes, events and people in Indonesia, Thailand and other Southeast Asian countries, circa 1950-1970 (Folder A-D)
  - 278 slides. Same as A-D, circa 1950-1970 (Folder slide cabinet)
- MICROFILMS, circa 1950-1960. (Cabinet microfilm cabinet)
  Arranged alphabetically by title of contents.
  - ANETA General News and Telegraph Agency, Economic News Report, 1954-56 (Reel 1-4)
  - Antara News, 1957, 1959 (Reel 5-11)
  - Antara and ANETA, 1957 (Reel 12)
  - Financial Economic Report, 1954-59 (Reel 13-20)
  - Monografi (Reel 21)
  - Miscellaneous excerpts from the Indonesian press and other sources pertaining to Indonesia (Reel 22-35)
- MOTION PICTURE REEL, 1959. (Cabinet film shelf)
  - Film of interview with D. Aidit and Sukarno, January 1959. (Reel film shelf)
- Incremental Materials (Box 176-306)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described. Contact us at hooverarchivesinfo@stanford.edu